ehl.ch 2012-02-21

# Privacy policy / Home - Lausanne Hotel School

## **Privacy policy**

**Privacy at Ecole hôtelière de Lausanne**  
Ecole hôtelière de Lausanne is committed to protecting the privacy of our web site visitors and clients. We uphold the highest industry standards in online privacy and permission marketing. For more information on how Ecole hôtelière de Lausanne enforces permission email marketing with our clients, please see our Anti-spam policy.

**Security and Privacy**  
Ecole hôtelière de Lausanne's web site uses security measures to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. We store the information in a database in a secure environment at our data center.  
We will never share, sell, or rent individual personal information with anyone without your advance permission or unless ordered by a court of law. Information submitted to us is only available to employees managing this information for purposes of contacting you or sending you e-mails based on your requesting information.

**Choice Opt-in**  
Our members and their subscribers are given the opportunity to 'opt-in' to having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for the information.  
Users of our site will always be notified if their information is being collected by any outside parties. We do this to ensure that our users can make an informed choice as to whether or not they should proceed with services that require an outside party.

**Newsletters**  
You will be added to Ecole hôtelière de Lausanne's email newsletter list only if you register to receive newsletters via a form on the Ecole hôtelière de Lausanne website. You may opt-out of receiving our newsletters by clicking on the opt-out link included in every email newsletter we send, or by contacting info@ehl.edu.

**Refer a Friend/Forward-to-a-Friend Functionality**  
If you feel that information about Ecole hôtelière de Lausanne could be useful for a third party you know (e.g. your friends or family members etc.), you may use our forward-to-a-friend functionality. If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about Ecole hôtelière de Lausanne, we will ask you for your friend's email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Ecole hôtelière de Lausanne stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program.  

**Testimonials**  
We post video customer testimonials on our web site which may contain personally identifiable information such as the customer's name. We obtain the customer's consent prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial.  

**Information Tracked**  
At times we will use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our web site. We also may track browser types to help us understand our visitors' needs related to our web site design.  
There is an optional section of our web site where input forms require your name, phone number, company, and e-mail address. This form provides the ability to opt-in to receiving future emails of any sort from Ecole hôtelière de Lausanne. If you opt-in to receiving email communications from us, then we may send information to you on our products or services.  
This information will not be used for any other purpose. We do, however, reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site.  
You may review and change your information with us at any time by clicking on the "modify profile" link on the site or similar found at the bottom of emails sent via our system, or by contacting us at info@ehl.edu   
To opt-out from having any provided information used for email communications from us, please click on the opt-out (unsubscribe) link in any message you receive from us. This will allow you to unsubscribe or update your message preferences. Alternately, you may contact us at info@ehl.edu .

**Web Beacons**  
In order to determine a user's ability to receive HTML email in addition to whether or not an email has been opened, Ecole hôtelière de Lausanne includes a “web beacon” in a majority of the HTML email messages we send. A web beacon (actually a small .gif image) is activated when an HTML email is opened via a request for the image on our servers.  
This capability helps Ecole hôtelière de Lausanne send email in a format users can read and enables Ecole hôtelière de Lausanne, and our clients that use the functionality, to track the aggregate number of emails opened. The web beacon does not collect any personally identifiable information. Users that do not want to receive email messages with web beacons can choose to receive their emails in text (non-HTML) format.  
We also use, and provide our clients with, the capability to track when a URL has been clicked inside of an email message sent by our system. We use this functionality to track which links were clicked and in what quantity, as well as the aggregate number of links clicked. This click tracking functionality does not collect any personally identifiable information.

**Cookies**  
Client-side cookies are used to verify the login status of customers using products or services linked directly with our website. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our site; however, the user may not be able to access all areas of our site.  
Links to other Websites   
Ecole hôtelière de Lausanne is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any other web sites to which we link.

**Safe Data Privacy Notice**  
Ecole hôtelière de Lausanne adheres to the Safe Principles published by the U.S. Department of Commerce (the "Safe Principles") with respect to personal information (as defined below) it receives from the European Union.  
Ecole hôtelière de Lausanne will respond to your request to access or delete personal information within 30 days as is required under the EU Safe Harbor program.  
This notice outlines our general policy and practices for implementing the Safe Principles, including the type of information to which this notice applies, how we use personal information, and the choices individuals have regarding our use of, and their ability to correct, that personal information. If there is any conflict between the policies in this notice and the Safe Principles, the Safe Principles will govern.  
This notice applies to all personal information we handle, including on-line (except as noted below), and manually processed data. For purposes of this notice, "personal information" means data that: is transferred from the European Union to the United States; is recorded in any form; and is about, or pertains to, a specific individual who is identified in, or is identifiable from, the data.  
"Sensitive information" is a subcategory of personal information. Sensitive information is defined as personal information specifying medical or health conditions, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, or the sex life of the individual. Sensitive information also includes personal information received from a third party where the third party treats and identifies it as sensitive.

 **Safe Principles Regarding Personal Information**

**Notice and Choice**  
We notify individuals about the personal information we collect from them, how we use it, and how to contact us with privacy concerns. We obtain personal information only as permitted by the Safe Principles or with the consent of the individual affected. Consent for personal information to be collected, used, and/or disclosed in certain ways may be required in order for an individual to obtain or use our services. To the extent permitted under the Safe , we reserve the right to process personal information in the course of providing professional services to our clients without the knowledge of individuals involved.

**Disclosures and Transfers**  
We do not disclose personal information to third parties, except when one or more of the following conditions is true:

  * We have the individual's permission to make the disclosure;
  * The disclosure is permitted by law or mandatory professional standards;
  * The disclosure is reasonably related to the sale or other disposition of all or part of our business or assets;
  * The personal information to be disclosed is publicly available;
  * The party to whom the disclosure is made controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with Ecole hôtelière de Lausanne;
  * The disclosure is reasonably necessary for the establishment or maintenance of legal claims; or
  * The disclosure is to persons or entities for whom we are providing services, provided the disclosure is consistent with the purpose for which the personal information was obtained.

We will comply with the Safe Principles with respect to disclosures of sensitive information, including, when applicable, obtaining the explicit consent of the individual prior to disclosing sensitive information to a third party or using sensitive information for purposes other than those for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by the individual. Transfers of information permitted under this notice, either to third parties or within Ecole hôtelière de Lausanne, include the transfer of data from one jurisdiction to another, such as transfers to and from Switzerland.

**Data Security, Integrity, and Access**  
We employ physical, electronic, and managerial measures, including education and training of our personnel, designed to provide the personal information in our possession with reasonable protection from accidental loss or destruction, improper use, alteration, or disclosure. Personal information collected or displayed through a web site is protected in transit by industry standard encryption processes. However, we cannot guarantee the security of personal information accessible on or transmitted via the Internet.  
We process personal information in ways compatible with the purpose for which the personal information was collected, or as otherwise authorized by the individual. To the extent necessary for such purposes, we take reasonable steps to make sure that personal information is accurate, complete, current, and otherwise reliable with regard to its intended use.  
If an individual becomes aware that personal information we maintain about that individual is inaccurate, or if an individual would like to update or review his or her personal information, the individual may contact us using the contact information below. As a security precaution, we may request that the individual provide identifying information such as name, address, birth date, and/or social security number. In some circumstances, we may charge a reasonable fee, where warranted, for access to personal information.

**Notification of Changes**  
Any new policy will be posted on our site at least one week prior to its taking effect. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner.  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, or the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.  
We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our website.

**Privacy Policy Effective Date: January 29, 2009**  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement or this web site, please contact us at: info@ehl.edu.
